# Amit Sarkar San Jose, CA 95123

E-mail: amit\_121@hotmail.com Mobile: (408) 644-6055

For past 15 years worked literally as a hub of the software development process, making sure the right people are given the right information to do their jobs. As a program manager was responsible for customers' success on the AWS platform. This is largely a customer facing role with a strong technical angle, including both hands on and higher-level architecture and thought leadership components. As a result successfully developed many web application/ mobile app products that collectively created over \$20 million revenue stream for the customers.

Certifications: AWS Certified Developer, AWS Certified Solution Architect, Certified Scrum Master, PMI Certified Project Manager (PMP)

AWS SysOps Admin Certification is pending and will be available soon.

#### **Skills Summary:**

AWS Solution Architect
Scaling Docker on AWS
AWS Cloud Formation
Puppet / Git /Jenkins
Systems Engineering
AWS Cloud
Mirgration to AWS Cloud
Mirgration to AWS Cloud
Testing/QA/Rollout/Support
Project Scheduling
Requirement Analysis
Custom Software Development
AWS Cost Management
Agile Transformation
Testing/QA/Rollout/Support
Bash Scripting

**Areas of Expertise:** Expert-level knowledge of Amazon EC2, Amazon S3, Amazon RDS, Amazon Elastic Load Balancing, Amazon SQS, and other services of the AWS family. Well versed with High-Availability, Fault Tolerance, Scalability, Database Concepts, System and Software, Architecture, Security, IT Infrastructure, Virtualization, and Internet Technologies.

Well Versed with Automatic Source Code Management using GIT and Continuous Integration using Jenkins. Hands of experience in Infrastructure -as-Code and Puppet.

Solid undersatning of System monitoring using Nagios and its components, New Relics .

**Hands on experience in configuration management using Cloud Formation.** Solid understanding of application, server, and network security and government requirements such as HIPAA.

Agile Principals, Iterative Development, Communication, Project Management, Iteration / Sprint Planning Meetings, Conflict Resolution, Tasking Meetings / Retrospectives, Relative Estimation, Story-Based Development, Backlog Tracking, Burndown Metrics, Velocity and Task definition. Expert in software development processes and procedures. Extensive expertise in SaaS/Cloud based product development projects. Completed over 10 multi tenancy based SaaS products. Completed a huge SaaS product using agile framework which is being implemented in several countries. Experienced in Full stack web-based systems programming and development using .Net/VB/C#/ C++, Ruby on rails, HTM, CSS, JavaScript, Mongo dB, ngnix, Ubuntu and Git on AWS cloud.

### **Experience:**

Japuram Inc. DBA Circar Consulting and Rorguru Director – Program Management October 2008- To date

Responsible for program management for software development activities and cloud deployment. Established AWS cloud infrastructure for the customers. Helped customers build scalable, resilient, and high-performance applications and services on AWS using well architected AWS framework that consist of security, reliability, performance efficiency and cost optimization. Developed/captured/documented architectural best practices for building systems on AWS. Managed large and significant cross-functional programs and projects. Defined and reviewed systems-level technical designs and user models. Led and organized key architecture discussions and decisions. Balanced near term business needs with long term implications.

Led complex, multi-disciplinary product development projects that were deployed on AWS cloud.

**Driven projects to completion on time.** Highlighted risks and clearly communicated those risks to stakeholders. Identified impediments and facilitated the removal of those impediments. Managed communication of progress/status with the team and other project stakeholders.

Estimated work efforts and proactively remove obstacles to drive momentum and progress. Managed issue escalations and provided support to teams and set priorities.

**Identified customers' needs to define product requirements.** Worked as a hub of software development activities. Facilitated and managed technical projects and company-wide programs. worked closely with multiple engineering teams, analytics, operations, and other cross-functional partners.

Brainstormed with the team, and the stakeholders to turn incomplete, conflicting, or ambiguous inputs into solid action plans. Beyond just shipping new products, created a culture for continuous product improvement, which create values in multiple of X.

**Extensively used agile framework and managed several** teams of software engineers and analysts that can roll out new functionality in a matter of weeks, not months. Created a culture to release features without any technical debt.

Transformed the company's project management practices to complete agile that included but not limited to creating agile roadmap, grooming true agile agents (champions) across multiple teams, company-wide agile training, implementing agile assessment to promote transparency in the organization etc.

Developed many web application/ mobile apps products / projects for our customers with value creation over 30X.

Managed and executed over 30 major product development projects. Worked as an agile expert for several successful web / mobile app products including several SaaS products that generated over \$20 million revenue streams for customers.

Used agile framework to develop a huge SaaS product that is being implemented in several dozen countries by several Fortune 500 companies. (Customers that using this product are; Unilever, *Toyota, Astra Zeneca, Kraft food, Heineken, Forest lab IBM, Hyundai, Mercedes, P&G, Colgate, Adidas* and many others.

Developed a successful ecommerce product that took the customer to public and later on acquired by another company.

Developed an agile product that was approved by Google and listed on Google market place.

Developed a successful product for a Silicon Valley startup that was listed among top 10 consumer start up by CIO magazine.

Substantial experience in all phases of Software development – Over 20 years.

Experienced in working with geo-distributed teams in various time zones. Excellent verbal and written communication skills, very strong abilities in critical thinking and technical analysis, troubleshooting and problem solving.

### Abacus Software Project Manager

Jan 2006- Sept 2008

Coordinated with participants and stakeholders to develop a detailed Project Plan for assigned projects. Prepared project scope, statements of work, work breakdown structures, task estimates, and specific tasks and milestones. Planned resources and schedule for project/program implementation. Created strategies for risk mitigation and contingency planning.

# Semantic Soft lean, San Jose, CA

**April 2003 – November 2005** 

# **Product Manager**

The Company developed a lean process and project management software product for the construction industry. Worked with the engineering team to develop a unique, superior & differentiated product with a strong market orientation. Defined market attractiveness and competencies. Established proper communication flow between the product and the engineering groups. Identified, tracked and resolved inter group issues. Also tracked actual results and performances against the software plans.

# Internet Speech, San Jose, CA Management Analyst

Worked closely with development team and created product roadmap and development timelines. Initiated, planned executed and monitored product development project along with the product development team. This includes development of the product scope, schedule and budget, risk identification, project team formation, creation of work breaks down structure, assignment of roles and responsibilities to the team members etc.

Conducted Market research & product positioning. Identified potential partners. Also Raised \$5 million series B fund from the second largest VC in Japan.

### **Education:**

University/College: Jackson State University, Jackson, MS.

Degree: MBA. (Graduated with Beta, Gamma and Sigma, the higshest national scholastic honor in USA)

University/College: School of Aviation & Tech (Ae.S.I), India

**Degree:** B.S (Aeronautical Engineering)

### **Industry Certifications:**

Organization: Project Management Institute

Certification: Project Management Professional (PMP)

Year: 2008

Organization: Scrum Alliance

Certification: Certified Scrum Master

Year: 2010

**Organization: AWS Web Services** 

**Certification: Certified AWS Solution Architect** 

**Certified AWS Developer** 

Year: 2016

Recent articles published: Avaiable upon requiest.